<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-10T18:58:05+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Interested in computer vision, AI, bioinformatics and HCI. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Paper on snoRNA-disease association prediction published in Computers in Biology and Medicine!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/GBDTSVM/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper on snoRNA-disease association prediction published in Computers in Biology and Medicine!"/><published>2025-04-24T00:12:13+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-24T00:12:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/GBDTSVM</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/GBDTSVM/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="gbdtsvm-combined-support-vector-machine-and-gradient-boosting-decision-tree-framework-for-efficient-snorna-disease-association-prediction">GBDTSVM: Combined Support Vector Machine and Gradient Boosting Decision Tree Framework for efficient snoRNA-disease association prediction</h2> <p>Excited to share our latest research published in Computers in Biology and Medicine (Q1)!</p> <p>Our paper introduces GBDTSVM, a novel machine learning framework that efficiently predicts snoRNA-disease associations by integrating Gradient Boosting Decision Trees (GBDT) and Support Vector Machines (SVM). With superior performance on multiple datasets, this model offers a powerful tool for advancing snoRNA-related disease research.</p> <p>Check out the full paper and source code here: Paper Link: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiomed.2025.110219">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiomed.2025.110219</a></p> <p>Source Code:</p> <p><a href="https://github.com/mariamuna04/gbdtsvm">https://github.com/mariamuna04/gbdtsvm</a></p> <p>Congrats and grateful to my authors Ummay Maria Muna, and our supervisor, Riasat Azim!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paper on snoRNA-disease association prediction published in Computers in Biology and Medicine!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paper on education design published in Computer Applications in Engineering Education!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/micropaper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper on education design published in Computer Applications in Engineering Education!"/><published>2025-02-20T00:12:13+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:12:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/micropaper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/micropaper/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="paper-titled-design-of-a-microprocessors-and-microcontrollers-laboratory-course-addressing-complex-engineering-problems-and-activities-published-in-computer-applications-in-engineering-education-focused-on-desigining-novel-curriculum-and-education-environment">Paper titled “Design of a Microprocessors and Microcontrollers Laboratory Course Addressing Complex Engineering Problems and Activities” published in Computer Applications in Engineering Education focused on Desigining Novel Curriculum and Education environment</h2> <p>We are thrilled to announce that our first paper in the field of Education, titled “Design of a Microprocessors and Microcontrollers Laboratory Course Addressing Complex Engineering Problems and Activities”, has been accepted for publication in the prestigious journal “Computer Applications in Engineering Education” by Wiley. This journal is ranked Q1 in both Engineering and Education categories, with an impact factor of 2.0.</p> <p>In this work, we proposed an innovative Laboratory course featuring open-ended labs designed to enable students to solve complex engineering problems and experience complex engineering activities. As we celebrate this milestone, it’s also a reminder that the journey of improvement never stops—it’s time to revisit and enhance the course curriculum once again, technology has evolved that fast! Here’s to continuous learning, innovation, and pushing the boundaries of engineering and HCI to enhance education curriculum!</p> <p>Check out the preprint and full paper here:</p> <p>Preprint Link: <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.05741">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.05741</a></p> <p>Paper Link: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/cae.70006">https://doi.org/10.1002/cae.70006</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paper on education design published in Computer Applications in Engineering Education!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Received crests for my lead role in the CSE Fest 2025 from Vice Chancellor, United International University(UIU)!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/CSE_Fest_25_crest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Received crests for my lead role in the CSE Fest 2025 from Vice Chancellor, United International University(UIU)!"/><published>2025-02-18T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/CSE_Fest_25_crest</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2025/CSE_Fest_25_crest/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="uiu-cse-fest-2025-a-grand-celebration-of-technology-and-innovation">UIU CSE Fest 2025: A Grand Celebration of Technology and Innovation</h2> <p>The Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) department of United International University (UIU) recently organized a spectacular technology festival, the UIU CSE Fest 2025. This two-day event saw enthusiastic participation from students across the country, showcasing their technological skills and innovative ideas. Nearly fifteen hundred students took part in various competitions, making the event truly impressive.</p> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/Fest25-collage1.jpg?raw=true" alt="Some moments from the UIU CSE Fest." width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Some moments from the UIU CSE Fest.</figcaption> <h3 id="my-role-treasurer-and-robotics-segment-coordinator">My Role: Treasurer and Robotics Segment Coordinator</h3> <p>I played two significant roles in this large-scale event – Treasurer and Robotics Segment Coordinator. As Treasurer, my responsibilities included managing the budgets for different segments, food arrangements, prize money, and concert organization. Simultaneously, as the Robotics Segment Coordinator, I played a key role in planning and conducting the robot-related competitions.</p> <h3 id="what-i-learned">What I Learned</h3> <p>Organizing such a large event taught me a great deal. My skills in time management, teamwork, financial planning, and handling unexpected situations were significantly enhanced. Furthermore, I had the opportunity to interact with students from all over the country, which enriched my knowledge and experience.</p> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/Fest25-Crest.jpg?raw=true" alt="Receiving the crest from the Vice Chancellor of UIU and guests at the closing ceremony." width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Receiving the crest from the Vice Chancellor of UIU and guests at the closing ceremony.</figcaption> <h3 id="recognition">Recognition</h3> <p>As recognition for my work, I received crests from the VC and guests at the closing ceremony. This recognition is a source of immense pride for me and inspires me to work even harder in the future.</p> <h3 id="cse-fest-2025-a-glimpse">CSE Fest 2025: A Glimpse</h3> <p>The fest featured exciting competitions like Line Following Robot, Robo Soccer, Blockchain Olympiad, Programming Contest, Project Show, and ICT Olympiad. There were also various outdoor games, badminton, and table tennis competitions.</p> <h3 id="some-notable-moments">Some Notable Moments</h3> <ul> <li>The International University of Scholars’ Team RoboMore Dynamic Sparks emerged as the champion in the Line Following Robot competition.</li> <li>Two UIU teams, Blue Beetle and C101, secured the champion and first runner-up positions respectively in Robo Soccer.</li> <li>The Blockchain Olympiad saw Yet Another One from Dhaka University win the gold medal.</li> <li>DU Primordials from Dhaka University were crowned champions in the UIU Inter-University Programming Contest.</li> </ul> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/Fest25-collage2.jpg?raw=true" alt="A glimpse of other exciting moments from the UIU CSE Fest." width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">A glimpse of other exciting moments from the UIU CSE Fest.</figcaption> <p>The UIU CSE Fest 2025 was a truly successful event, pushing the boundaries of students’ technological knowledge and innovative thinking.</p> <p>Learn more about the UIU CSE Fest:</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://csefest.uiu.ac.bd/">CSE Fest Website</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=61569420809397">CSE Fest Facebook Page</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Received crests for my lead role in the CSE Fest 2025 from Vice Chancellor, United International University(UIU)!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Received crests for my organizer role in CSE Project Show from Head of the Department, CSE, UIU!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/CSE_project_show242_crest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Received crests for my organizer role in CSE Project Show from Head of the Department, CSE, UIU!"/><published>2024-12-29T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-29T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/CSE_project_show242_crest</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/CSE_project_show242_crest/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="uiu-cse-project-show">UIU CSE Project Show</h2> <p>I am thrilled to share that I recently received a crest as one of the main organizers of the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/uiucseps/">“CSE Project show”</a> from the <a href="https://cse.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/mnh/">“Prof. Dr. Mohammad Nurul Huda”</a>, Head, Dept. of CSE, UIU and <a href="https://cse.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/muzahid/">“Prof. Dr. A.K.M. Muzahidul Islam”</a>, Dept. of CSE, UIU. This recognition is a testament to the hard work and dedication put into making the event a success.</p> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_5.jpeg?raw=true" alt="Receiving crest as the organizer from the Head of the Department, CSE, UIU" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Receiving crest as the organizer from the Head of the Department, CSE, UIU</figcaption> <p>Additionally, the UIU Robotics Club, which played a significant role in the project show, also received crests. Their collaboration and support were crucial in organizing and executing the event successfully. Thanks to UIU Robotics Club President, Mr. Ahmed Junaid Tanim, Ms. Faria Rakib Borsha (GS, UIU Robotics Club), Mr. Rashique Chowdhury (Treasurer, UIU Robotics Club) and others for their significant role. As the moderator of UIU Robotics club, I am proud to have them by our side.</p> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_6.jpeg?raw=true" alt="UIU Robotics Club receiving crest as one of the main partners in the prestigious event" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">UIU Robotics Club receiving crest as one of the main partners in the prestigious event</figcaption> <p>The recognition we received is not just a personal achievement but a reflection of the collective effort of the entire team. Thank you to everyone who contributed to the success of the UIU Summer Project Show 2024!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Received crests for my organizer role in CSE Project Show from Head of the Department, CSE, UIU!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Excited to work as one of the coordinator and Treasurer of UIU CSE Fest-2025!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/csefest.uiu.ac.bd/gratitude" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Excited to work as one of the coordinator and Treasurer of UIU CSE Fest-2025!"/><published>2024-12-02T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-02T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/csefest.uiu.ac.bd/csefest_uiu_25</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/csefest.uiu.ac.bd/gratitude"><![CDATA[<h2 id="about-uiu-cse-fest-2025">About UIU CSE Fest 2025</h2> <p>UIU CSE Fest 2025 is a premier event designed to celebrate innovation, collaboration, and learning within the computer science and engineering community. This fest aims to create a vibrant platform where students, industry professionals, and tech enthusiasts come together to explore cutting-edge advancements in Programming, Software Development, and Robotics.</p> <p>The fest features a variety of engaging events, including the UIU IUPC 2025, Blockchain Olympiad, Project Show, ICT Olympiad, and exciting robotics competitions like the Soccer Bot Competition and Line Follower Robot Competition. Each event is structured to encourage participation, foster creativity, and showcase the talents of aspiring engineers.</p> <p>Through UIU CSE Fest 2025, we aim to empower participants with the knowledge and skills necessary for success in the rapidly evolving tech landscape. We invite you to join us in making this event a transformative experience for all involved, inspiring the next generation of leaders in technology and innovation.</p> <p>Check out our organizing team members: <a href="https://csefest.uiu.ac.bd/gratitude">“Central Organizing Committee of UIU CSE FEST-2025”</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Excited to work as one of the coordinator and Treasurer of UIU CSE Fest-2025!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paper on Rapid Kit Test results prediction from smartphone is arXived!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/arxiv.org/pdf/2411.18007" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper on Rapid Kit Test results prediction from smartphone is arXived!"/><published>2024-11-27T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/arxiv.org/pdf/rapid_kit_arxiv</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/arxiv.org/pdf/2411.18007"><![CDATA[<h2 id="ai-driven-smartphone-solution-for-digitizing-rapid-diagnostic-test-kits-and-enhancing-accessibility-for-the-visually-impaired">AI-Driven Smartphone Solution for Digitizing Rapid Diagnostic Test Kits and Enhancing Accessibility for the Visually Impaired</h2> <p>Rapid diagnostic tests are crucial for timely disease detection and management, yet accurate interpretation of test results remains challenging. In this study, we propose a novel approach to enhance the accuracy and reliability of rapid diagnostic test result interpretation by integrating artificial intelligence (AI) algorithms, including convolutional neural networks (CNN), within a smartphone-based application. The app enables users to take pictures of their test kits, which YOLOv8 then processes to precisely crop and extract the membrane region, even if the test kit is not centered in the frame or is positioned at the very edge of the image. This capability offers greater accessibility, allowing even visually impaired individuals to capture test images without needing perfect alignment, thus promoting user independence and inclusivity. The extracted image is analyzed by an additional CNN classifier that determines if the results are positive, negative, or invalid, providing users with the results and a confidence level. Through validation experiments with commonly used rapid test kits across various diagnostic applications, our results demonstrate that the synergistic integration of AI significantly improves sensitivity and specificity in test result interpretation. This improvement can be attributed to the extraction of the membrane zones from the test kit images using the state-of-the-art YOLO algorithm. Additionally, we performed SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) analysis to investigate the factors influencing the model’s decisions, identifying reasons behind both correct and incorrect classifications. By facilitating the differentiation of genuine test lines from background noise and providing valuable insights into test line intensity and uniformity, our approach offers a robust solution to challenges in rapid test interpretation.</p> <p>Check out the paper: <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.18007">“archived version”</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paper on Rapid Kit Test results prediction from smartphone is arXived!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Checkout my latest work: Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/github.com/FahimHafiz/LTspice-integration-with-Matlab-and-Python" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Checkout my latest work: Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB"/><published>2024-10-24T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-24T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/github.com/FahimHafiz/circuit_automation24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/github.com/FahimHafiz/LTspice-integration-with-Matlab-and-Python"><![CDATA[<p>Checkout my latest work <a href="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/LTspice-integration-with-Matlab-and-Python">“Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB”</a> which makes the circuit analysis easier and more interesting!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Checkout my latest work: Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB, which makes the circuit analysis easier and more interesting!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glad to be organising another project show at UIU!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/www.facebook.com/uiucseps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glad to be organising another project show at UIU!"/><published>2024-10-07T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/www.facebook.com/CSE_project_show24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/www.facebook.com/uiucseps/"><![CDATA[<p>Hectic yet had an amazing experience while organising the project show, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/uiucseps/">“Project show, UIU”</a>. I was one of the main organiser on behalf of the CSE Department, UIU along with <a href="https://cse.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/muzahid/">“Prof. Dr. A.K.M. Muzahidul Islam”</a> and <a href="https://cse.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/shoib/">“Lecturer Shoib Ahmed”</a>. The details of the project show is summarised here:</p> <h2 id="uiu-summer-2024s-project-show">UIU Summer 2024’s Project Show</h2> <p><strong>A Collaborative Showcase of Innovation from CSE and EEE Students!</strong></p> <p>The Departments of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) and Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE) at United International University (UIU) proudly hosted the Summer Project Show 2024 on <strong>Monday, October 7, 2024</strong>. In this event, the students showcased over <strong>320 projects from CSE</strong> and <strong>70 projects from EEE</strong>, spanning <strong>11 categories</strong> and drawing a diverse audience of students, faculty, and industry experts.</p> <p>Participants displayed a wide array of innovations in fields like <strong>electronics, microprocessors, advanced programming, database management, system analysis</strong>, and <strong>software engineering</strong>. Notably, <strong>Data Science students</strong> contributed their unique perspectives, enriching the event’s diversity. The show aimed to inspire creativity, promote teamwork, and enhance students’ confidence and presentation skills.</p> <h3 id="event-organizers">Event Organizers</h3> <p>Organized by the <strong>UIU App Forum</strong>, <strong>UIU Robotics Club</strong>, and <strong>UIU Electrical &amp; Electronics Club</strong>, the event was a testament to the hard work and talent of the participants. Exceptional projects in both software and hardware were recognized, encouraging students to continue exploring new ideas and technologies.</p> <h3 id="distinguished-judges">Distinguished Judges</h3> <p>The judging panel included distinguished guests, featuring representatives from both CSE and EEE:</p> <ul> <li><strong>CSE Judges:</strong> <ul> <li>Dr. ABM Alim Al Islam, Professor at BUET</li> <li>Prof. Dr. Md. Golam Rabiul Alam, from BRAC University</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_1.jpg?raw=true" alt="Prof. Dr. Md. Golam Rabiul Alam is received by me and the volunteer students!" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Prof. Dr. Md. Golam Rabiul Alam is received by me and the volunteer students!</figcaption> <ul> <li><strong>EEE Judges:</strong> <ul> <li>Md. Mizanur Rahman, Assistant Engineer (Implementation) at SCUBE Technologies Ltd.</li> <li>Sifat-Ul-Alam, Sr. Assistant Director at Walton High Tech Industries PLC</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_2.jpg?raw=true" alt="Honorable Judges evaluating the projects" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Honorable Judges evaluating the projects</figcaption> <h3 id="event-highlights">Event Highlights</h3> <p>The Summer 2024 Project Show highlighted UIU’s commitment to fostering innovation, enhancing skills, and bridging the gap between academia and industry. <strong>Prof. Dr. Md. Abul Kashem Mia</strong>, Vice Chancellor of UIU, commended the participants and winners for their remarkable contributions, expressing hopes for their continued success. The prize-giving ceremony was also graced with the presence of esteemed faculty members, including <strong>Dr. Raqibul Mostofa</strong>, <strong>Dr. Mohammad Nurul Huda</strong>, <strong>Dr. AKM Muzahidul Islam</strong>, <strong>Dr. Md. Iqbal Bahar Chowdhury</strong>, <strong>Dr. Sadid Muneer</strong>, and <strong>Dr. Riasat Azim</strong>.</p> <h3 id="acknowledgments">Acknowledgments</h3> <p>Both the CSE and EEE departments thanked <strong>Mr. Shoib Ahmed</strong>, <strong>Mr. Zubair Ahmed</strong>, <strong>Mr. Fahim Hafiz</strong>, <strong>Mr. Haider Ali</strong>, and <strong>S.M. Monzurul Hoque Chowdhury</strong> for their invaluable coordination in making the event a success.</p> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_3.jpg?raw=true" alt="Prize Giving Ceremony1" width="900"/> <img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_4.JPG?raw=true" alt="Prize Giving Ceremony2" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Prize Giving Ceremony of the Project Show-Summer 24</figcaption>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Glad to be organising another project show at UIU!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I attended a workshop titled AI in Public Health organized by CHRF, Bangladesh</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/chrfbd.org/blogs/474f2f3e-7c9e-402f-9ed6-c17cec81a7d9" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I attended a workshop titled AI in Public Health organized by CHRF, Bangladesh"/><published>2024-06-01T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-01T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/chrfbd.org/blogs/AI_public_health24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/chrfbd.org/blogs/474f2f3e-7c9e-402f-9ed6-c17cec81a7d9"><![CDATA[<p>I had an amazing experience participating in a workshop titled <a href="https://chrfbd.org/blogs/474f2f3e-7c9e-402f-9ed6-c17cec81a7d9">“AI in Public Health”</a> organized by Child Health Research Foundation (CHRF), Bangladesh. This five-day workshop focused on exploring the role of AI in public health and how policy should be adopted in recent times. This five days workshop was taken by three esteemed researchers in their respective area: -Senjuti Saha, PhD, Deputy Executive Director, Child Health Research Foundation (CHRF) -Yogesh Hooda, PhD, Lead, Biochemistry and Molecular Biology Laboratory -Sudipta Saha, PhD student, Department of Social and Behavioral Sciences, Hardvard University</p> <p>In this workshop, basics of data visualization of vaccination datasets, data cleaning and analyzing using python and prediction on dengue datasets (time series) using machine learning was taught. Furthermore, deep learning aspects was also discussed. Moreover, how disease modelling is performed along with health policy and recent trends of AI as well as it’s ethical perspective was discussed.</p> <p>Here is a session on utilizing AI in Public health by Mr. Sudipta Saha.. <img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/chrf24_1.jpeg?raw=true" alt="AI in Public Health Session taken by Mr. Sudipta Saha" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">AI in Public Health Session taken by Mr. Sudipta Saha!</figcaption> <p>Here are some moments from this wonderful workshop!</p> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/chrf24_3.jpeg?raw=true" alt="Memorable moments with the friends/participants from this workshop where we met for the first time!" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Memorable moments with the friends/participants from this workshop where we met for the first time!</figcaption> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/chrf24_4.jpeg?raw=true" alt="Receiving the workshop certificate from Dr. Senjuti Saha and Dr. Yogesh Hooda!" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Receiving the workshop certificate from Dr. Senjuti Saha and Dr. Yogesh Hooda!</figcaption> <p>Here is the group photo with the amazing CHRF team on the last day of our workshop! <img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/chrf24_2.jpeg?raw=true" alt="Group photo with the amazing CHRF team" width="900"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Group photo with the amazing CHRF team</figcaption> <p>I intend to write the more technical learnings from this workshop in a series of lectures, specially the Machine Learning examples. Please keep an eye on my GitHub profile. Here is already the first series of my learning from this workshop: <a href="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/Vaccination-Dataset-Preprocessing-Analysis-and-Prediction-Using-Machine-Learning">“Vaccination Dataset Preprocessing Analysis and Prediction Using Machine Learning”</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I attended a workshop titled AI in Public Health organized by CHRF, Bangladesh]]></summary></entry></feed>