<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-11-01T11:01:14+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Interested in computer vision, AI, bioinformatics and HCI. </subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/2024-06-01-AI_public_health24/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2024-11-01T11:01:14+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T11:01:14+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/2024-06-01-AI_public_health24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/2024-06-01-AI_public_health24/"><![CDATA[<p>I had an amazing experience participating in a workshop titled <a href="https://chrfbd.org/blogs/474f2f3e-7c9e-402f-9ed6-c17cec81a7d9">“AI in Public Health”</a> organized by Child Health Research Foundation (CHRF), Bangladesh. This five-day workshop focused on exploring the role of AI in public health and how policy should be adopted in recent times. I shall share my learnings in detail in this post later!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Checkout my latest work: Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/github.com/FahimHafiz/LTspice-integration-with-Matlab-and-Python" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Checkout my latest work: Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB"/><published>2024-10-24T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-24T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/github.com/FahimHafiz/circuit_automation24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/github.com/FahimHafiz/LTspice-integration-with-Matlab-and-Python"><![CDATA[<p>Checkout my latest work <a href="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/LTspice-integration-with-Matlab-and-Python">“Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB”</a> which makes the circuit analysis easier and more interesting!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Checkout my latest work: Circuit Simulator Automation using Python and MATLAB, which makes the circuit analysis easier and more interesting!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glad to be organising another project show at UIU!</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/www.facebook.com/uiucseps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glad to be organising another project show at UIU!"/><published>2024-10-07T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/www.facebook.com/CSE_project_show24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/https:/www.facebook.com/uiucseps/"><![CDATA[<p>Hectic yet had an amazing experience while organising the project show, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/uiucseps/">“Project show, UIU”</a>. I was one of the main organiser on behalf of the CSE Department, UIU along with <a href="https://cse.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/muzahid/">“Prof. Dr. A.K.M. Muzahidul Islam”</a> and <a href="https://cse.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/shoib/">“Lecturer Shoib Ahmed”</a>. The details of the project show is summarised here:</p> <h2 id="uiu-summer-2024s-project-show">UIU Summer 2024’s Project Show</h2> <p><strong>A Collaborative Showcase of Innovation from CSE and EEE Students!</strong></p> <p>The Departments of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) and Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE) at United International University (UIU) proudly hosted the Summer Project Show 2024 on <strong>Monday, October 7, 2024</strong>. In this event, the students showcased over <strong>320 projects from CSE</strong> and <strong>70 projects from EEE</strong>, spanning <strong>11 categories</strong> and drawing a diverse audience of students, faculty, and industry experts.</p> <p>Participants displayed a wide array of innovations in fields like <strong>electronics, microprocessors, advanced programming, database management, system analysis</strong>, and <strong>software engineering</strong>. Notably, <strong>Data Science students</strong> contributed their unique perspectives, enriching the event’s diversity. The show aimed to inspire creativity, promote teamwork, and enhance students’ confidence and presentation skills.</p> <h3 id="event-organizers">Event Organizers</h3> <p>Organized by the <strong>UIU App Forum</strong>, <strong>UIU Robotics Club</strong>, and <strong>UIU Electrical &amp; Electronics Club</strong>, the event was a testament to the hard work and talent of the participants. Exceptional projects in both software and hardware were recognized, encouraging students to continue exploring new ideas and technologies.</p> <h3 id="distinguished-judges">Distinguished Judges</h3> <p>The judging panel included distinguished guests, featuring representatives from both CSE and EEE:</p> <ul> <li><strong>CSE Judges:</strong> <ul> <li>Dr. ABM Alim Al Islam, Professor at BUET</li> <li>Prof. Dr. Md. Golam Rabiul Alam, from BRAC University</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_1.jpg?raw=true" alt="Prof. Dr. Md. Golam Rabiul Alam is received by me and the volunteer students!"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Prof. Dr. Md. Golam Rabiul Alam is received by me and the volunteer students!</figcaption> <ul> <li><strong>EEE Judges:</strong> <ul> <li>Md. Mizanur Rahman, Assistant Engineer (Implementation) at SCUBE Technologies Ltd.</li> <li>Sifat-Ul-Alam, Sr. Assistant Director at Walton High Tech Industries PLC</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_2.jpg?raw=true" alt="Honorable Judges evaluating the projects"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Honorable Judges evaluating the projects</figcaption> <h3 id="event-highlights">Event Highlights</h3> <p>The Summer 2024 Project Show highlighted UIU’s commitment to fostering innovation, enhancing skills, and bridging the gap between academia and industry. <strong>Prof. Dr. Md. Abul Kashem Mia</strong>, Vice Chancellor of UIU, commended the participants and winners for their remarkable contributions, expressing hopes for their continued success. The prize-giving ceremony was also graced with the presence of esteemed faculty members, including <strong>Dr. Raqibul Mostofa</strong>, <strong>Dr. Mohammad Nurul Huda</strong>, <strong>Dr. AKM Muzahidul Islam</strong>, <strong>Dr. Md. Iqbal Bahar Chowdhury</strong>, <strong>Dr. Sadid Muneer</strong>, and <strong>Dr. Riasat Azim</strong>.</p> <h3 id="acknowledgments">Acknowledgments</h3> <p>Both the CSE and EEE departments thanked <strong>Mr. Shoib Ahmed</strong>, <strong>Mr. Zubair Ahmed</strong>, <strong>Mr. Fahim Hafiz</strong>, <strong>Mr. Haider Ali</strong>, and <strong>S.M. Monzurul Hoque Chowdhury</strong> for their invaluable coordination in making the event a success.</p> <p><img src="https://github.com/FahimHafiz/FahimHafiz.github.io/blob/main/assets/img/cseps24_3.jpg?raw=true" alt="Prize Giving Ceremony" width="300"/> <br/></p> <figcaption style="text-align: center;">Prize Giving Ceremony of the Project Show-Summer 24</figcaption>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Glad to be organising another project show at UIU!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fahimhafiz.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>